vnseo.com 2005-04-03

# Submit Express - Privacy Policy

Submit Express believes that strong electronic privacy is crucial for the ongoing success of the Internet as a service, commercial and entertainment medium. To this end, unless you designate otherwise, the information you enter here will be known to only two parties: you and Submit Express. We pledge that Submit Express will not release your personal data to anyone else without your consent - period. You may change the status of whether you wish to receive Submit Express offers and communications at any time. When we do present information to our advertisers, unless you tell us otherwise, it is in the form of aggregate statistics compiled among all of our visitors' answers to survey questions as well as grouped on-site behavior. 

1\. What information does Submit Express gather/track and how is it used?   
2\. With whom does Submit Express share the information it gathers/tracks?   
3\. What is Submit Express's unsubscribe and data-removal policy? 

**1\. What information does Submit Express gather/track and how is it used?**

**Use of traffic data**   
Each time a visitor comes to a Submit Express Web site, we collect some information to improve the overall quality of the online experience. At Submit Express content sites, we collect the visitor's domain name (e.g., whether the user is logged on from ibm.com or yale.edu), referral data (e.g., we record the address of the last URL a user visited prior to clicking through to a Submit Express Web site), and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on a Macintosh platform). The Submit Express site collects visitor information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement and targeted advertising. We also count, track and aggregate the visitor's activity into our analysis of general traffic flows at our sites (e.g. tracking where traffic comes from, how traffic flows within the Submit Express properties, etc.). To these ends, we may merge information about you into group data, which may then be shared on an aggregated basis with our advertisers; but Submit Express will not disclose your individual identity or personal data without your permission. When Submit Express does present aggregated information to outside companies, no one will be able to identify you or contact you. 

**Use of cookies**   
Submit Express Web sites may use cookies for internal reporting. Cookies are a standard Internet technology that allow us to both store and retrieve login information on a user's system. Other companies which place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that Submit Express does not control. However, cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines, so these advertisers will not know who you are - and Submit Express will not tell them without your consent. 

**Use of Email and URL Addresses Collected from Free Submission or META Tags Generator**  
Email and URL addresses used for our free submission and free META Tag generator are logged in a log file for tracking purposes and will not be used to send unsolicited email. The email addresses and URL addresses are forwarded in real time to various search engines via the free submission page. We have made sure in advance that the search engines we submit to do not use this information to send unsolicited email. However, please note that a few of these search engines may send you an auto response, confirming your submission

**Use of Email Addresses Collected from Newsletter and Mailing List Subscriptions**

After signing up to receive any of Submit Express Newsletters or mailing lists by email, users will start receiving newsletters or emails delivered on a daily, weekly, or monthly basis, as well as occasional product-related announcements. Note that every subscriber will go through a double opt-in process to make sure that no one gets subscribed accidentally. After a subscriber signs up on one of our sign up forms a confirmation email will be sent to the subscriber. The subscriber will only be added to our database when they confirm their subscription by replying to this email.

On Submit Express Web sites that offer newsletters, we collect subscribers' email addresses in order to distribute those newsletters and product-related announcements. In addition, Submit Express has entered into agreements with a number of other companies to distribute Submit Express newsletters and mailing lists to users on their systems. Submit Express newsletters and mailing lists are also offered in a number of Newsletter Partner sites, all of which require a user's email address for distribution. In the case of those email addresses collected by our Partners, email addresses are either forwarded to us for maintenance by Submit Express, or are kept and maintained exclusively by our Partners under privacy conditions acceptable to Submit Express. If you are concerned about the privacy policies of a Newsletter Partner site, please contact the webmaster of that site. 

Users can choose to unsubscribe from Submit Express newsletters or product-related announcements at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions found in each email. 

**Use of Data from Paid Submissions or Optimization Services**

All website information provided for our paid submission and optimization services will only be forwarded to search engines, directories and Free For All pages for listing purposes. All credit card information will be kept strictly confidential. Note that to avoid SPAM and unwanted email from automated replies for our 2500+ search engine submission, we will not provide your email address to the engines; instead we will provide them our own email address.

**2\. With whom does Submit Express share the information it gathers/tracks?**

** PostMasterDirect.com is a leading opt-in email provider that manages some of our newsletters and mailing lists on our behalf. Please see their privacy policy at:  
<http://w3.netcreations.com/main?page=privacy>

** Flycast is our third party banner advertising provider. We are required to place the note below per our agreement with them:  
"SUBMIT EXPRESS WORKS WITH A THIRD PARTY THAT SERVES ADS TO THIS SITE. TO FIND OUT MORE ABOUT HOW FLYCAST MANAGES THE PRIVACY OF INFORMATION IN CONJUNCTION WITH SERVING ADS ON THIS SITE, PLEASE GO TO: [Flycast Communications Privacy Policy](http://www.flycast.com/about_us/index.cfm?sub=pri&content=privacy)"

**Affiliate Programs  
** In addition, Submit Express works with the following companies that provide banner ads via affiliate programs: [BeFree](http://www.befree.com/), [Internet Domain Registrars](http://www.registrars.com/), [Commission Junction](http://www.cj.com/), [overture.com](http://www.overture.com/) and [ValueClick](http://www.valueclick.com/). Please check their sites for their privacy policies.

[Retriever and AccessPoint](http://www.apc.net/):  
Retriever and AccessPoint are third party merchant account providers. All credit card information collected for our paid services will be processed by them. Please see their privacy policy at:  
<http://www.apc.net/policies/privstate.html>

**3\. What is Submit Express's unsubscribe and data-removal policy?**

If you have agreed to allow Submit Express to make your information available to outside organizations, we will use our reasonably best efforts to ensure that your individual data is no longer distributed by Submit Express after your removal request. However, Submit Express is not responsible for the removal of your personal information from third-party lists if you have previously authorized Submit Express to distribute it.

From time to time, Submit Express may introduce new products and services to its users. To the extent these new products and services affect this policy, this policy will be updated. You will be informed of these updates and any privacy conditions related to these services.
